As we read the scripture today,
the message today is what you say
matters.
What you say
>> matters. I really appreciate the song
they sung because what you sing
>> matters.
The blessings that we have spoken, may
that be your portion.
>> Amen.
>> May that be your portion to your
children and your their children and
their children's children.
Amen.
So, we're going to read a passage
of people who say things
and in that generation
they mattered.
In this particular generation, they
mattered negatively.
But I pray that in Jesus name that in
our generation
what we say
will matter
positively to advance the kingdom. Amen.
And common utterance. So we want to read
numbers
14 1-10.
NIV and I read
that night all the members of the
community raised their voices
and wept aloud.
All the Israelites grumbled against
Moses and Aaron and the whole assembly
said remember what we say matters. They
said to them,
"If only we had died in Egypt
or in this wilderness,
what they said
matter because they died where?"
>> In that wilderness,
not God. God never said it. They said
it.
Why is the Lord bringing us to this land
only to let us fall by the sword?
our wives and children will be taken as
splendor.
And that's exactly what happened.
Wouldn't it be better for us to go back
to Egypt?
And then they said to each other,
"We should choose a leader and go back
to Egypt."
Then Moses and Aaron fell face down in
front of the whole Israel assembly
gathered there. Joshua son of Nan and
Calb son of Japun who among those who
had explored the land tore their clothes
and said
ah then say 10 said these things two
said another thing what percentage is
that
two said this 10 said that out of 12
it's about
about 20%.
and said to the entire Israel assembly,
"The land we pass through and explore is
exceedingly good.
If the Lord is pleased with us, he will
lead us into that land, a land flowing
with milk and honey, and he will give it
to us." Only do not rebel against the
Lord. And do not be afraid of the people
of the land, their giants,
because we will devour them.
Their protection is gone.
But the Lord
is with us.
Do not be afraid of them.
But the whole assembly talked about
stoning them. Then the glory of the Lord
appeared at the tent of meeting to all
the Israelites.
This is God's word. God's people said
it.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. We may be seated as I pray.
Father, we thank you.
A wonderful time of worship,
great moments of giving, of hearing and
fellowshipping together,
and now a moment to hear God's word. We
have read it.
Now Lord break it to us all to the glory
of your name. Those online, those in
person, may the Lord bless us. Those in
the pavilion, God blessing all of us.
Speak to our hearts because what we say
matters. Father, thank you for we have
prayed all these things in Jesus name
and gospel say
>> amen.
I have written a book
called Inspiring Leaders for Effective
Service. Pastor Simon talked about it.
And let me tell you this that every word
I've said in this book
matters.
Hallelujah.
Every word matters. And just for those
who may not have been here, the the
control team can give us a clip and then
I'll pick it from there.
Then he said to his disciples,
"The harvest truly is plentiful, but the
laborers are few.
Therefore, pray for the Lord of the
harvest to send out laborers into his
harvest."
In a world longing for direction, there
is a scarcity of leaders who inspire.
But you can make a difference. You have
been called to arise and shine.
Inspiring leaders for effective service
authored by Reverend Ambus Nyongo is a
guide calling you to lead through
effective service. These kingdom
principles equip you to bring in the
great harvest through the great
commission inspired by the great
commandment.
Invest in acquiring these kingdom
principles today and be equipped to
shepherd souls. Ignite transformation
and carry the message of Christ to the
ends of the world. Inspiring leaders for
effective service. Lead boldly. Serve
faithfully. Inspire generations.
[Applause]
Thank God for our brother Alex for
giving voice
uh to that message. God bless you Alex
Barton and he's still praying to go on
BBC.
Thank you Jesus. CNN,
thank you Jesus.
What you say matters
>> matters.
This book is for leaders. If you know
any leader who would be encouraged by
this book and especially your chief,
get a copy for your chief
and even the subchief. Uh get this book
to that police station where you stay,
that police superintendent in that
place. Get him this. It will change that
environment tremendously. But this book
is for you and I want to let you know
I've been writing it since 2018. Got to
finish it early early this year. And we
just I just really I'm proud of what I
wrote. I believe in what I said and I
know that leaders are not leaders until
they are serving. When you're serving,
your leadership is manifested. And so
serve. Serve. The Bible says, "The son
of man did not come to be served, but to
serve and to give his life as a ransom
for many." I just this morning I signed
a book uh to honorable Wangula, speaker
of the National Assembly that he may get
this copy and read it. I'm sending
another one to Governor Sakaja uh and
I'm sending another one to Hallelujah.
Fill in the blanks.
And if you're close to some of these
people and you'd like me to sign a copy
to them, let me know
because we want this word to go as far
as it can go.
What you say matters.
This month, Pastor Simon has spoken. I
spoke at the beginning of the month.
Last sun, last the other time, we had
Mother's Day and this word has been
spoken and spoken. We talked about the
tongue, the power of the tongue and what
God is able to do through the tongue.
The power of speech was only given to
human beings.
Animals communicate but they don't
speak. Birds communicate but they don't
speak. They don't have a speech.
Ants communicate in their own way. It is
only human beings that were given the
ability to communicate, to talk to one
another and to understand one another.
It is only human beings who are given
the ability to talk to God and for God
to talk to them. And therefore, it is
key for you to know that what you say
matters. In the Bible and the scripture
we read earlier, we find that the 10
spies went to spy. The the 12 spies went
to spy. They saw the same thing but they
reported different things. And we can
see the same thing but those same things
can impress us and
talk to us and we start saying things
that are not true. And so the 10 spies
came and they said the land is good. It
is lovely. There are many good things
there. But in that land there are
fortified cities. The other thing that
is there there are giants and they gave
a bad report to the people and they
began to scream. They began to weep.
They began to say we need to go back.
They created fear
and their destiny was stopped because of
what they said. Only Joshua and Calb
stood up and said the land we saw is
very good. But then he said, "The God
who sent us there, he will bring us to
that land." And I want you to know that
in Jesus name, it doesn't matter what
kind of obstacles you have met this
year, the God who has brought you this
far
will see you through
>> in Jesus name.
>> Hallelujah. Why don't we give him a big
hand and tell him thank you in Jesus
name.
This God is able. And so this God
depends so much on what we say. God will
do what he wants. But our speech gives
him permission to enter this planet and
to make things happen.
The devil also depends on our speech
because what you say empowers him to do
what he wants to do depending on what
you said.
One of the things the devil told Eve at
the beginning during the temptation, he
said, "Did God
say? Did God say?" Of course, God had
said, but God had actually told who?
Adam.
And it was the responsibility of Adam to
tell Eve what God said.
And so, the devil is challenging
Eve, did God say? And if he said it, are
you sure that's what he meant? But I
want to let you know that this word of
God is what God says and it is what he
means. If God says, "I will supply all
your needs according to my riches and
glory," that's exactly what he will do.
And so what we say is important because
it matters.
We're going to see three areas where our
speech goes. Number one, what you say
outward,
what you say inward,
what you say upward.
And I'll start with the first one. What
you say outward. It's saying to
authorize. What do you say to things and
the situations around you? What do you
say? Because God wants to authorize his
purposes into those situations and
circumstances.
Jesus Christ was walking one time and he
went to a fig tree and found a fig tree
that was thought he thought there was
fruit but when he reached there they
were just leaves. And so Jesus spoke
aloud. The disciples could hear him.
And Jesus said to the fig tree, "You
shall not bear any fruit forever." The
Bible says immediately that fig tree
withered from the roots
because what he said
mattered. Hallelujah.
The disciples come to him and says,
"Hey, by the way, the fig tree you are
talking to withered." And Jesus then
says these words. Mark chapter 11 verse
22. Let me start with 22 and I'll go to
24. He says this, "Have what?
Faith in God." Jesus answered, "Truly I
tell you, if anyone says to this
mountain,
go throw yourself into the sea and has
not doubt in their heart but believes
that what they say say will happen, it
will be done for them."
Hallelujah.
What you say, what you say. Then he
talked about this mountain. When God
says this mountain, he's dealing with
situations in your life that don't seem
to change
that have been there for a long time.
They're always looking at you and you're
always looking at them.
Things in your family lineage that seem
to have been set and there will not
change. Let me tell you this. God is a
God who makes things change.
Hallelujah.
But God is saying, "Yes, I want to
change them, but I'm depending on what
you say to the mountain. Say to this
mountain,
go throw yourself to the sea and it will
be done
not according to God's will.
It will be done because you have done
what you have said. What you say matters
and especially when you speak outward,
what you say outward, what you say to
the mountains.
God took a long time trying to convince
Abraham that he was serious when he told
him, I will bless you and make you
great. So, let me read those verses in
Genesis 12 verse 1 to3.
The Bible says this.
The Lord said to Abraham, "Go from your
country, your people, and your father's
household to the land I will show you."
Then God says, "I will make you into a
great nation." Now, ladies and
gentlemen, when God speaks, pay
attention.
Hello.
When God speaks, pay attention because
he means what he says. And he says what
he means.
I will make you into a great nation and
I will bless you.
Next verse.
I will make your name great
and you will be a blessing. I will bless
those who bless you and whoever curses
you I will do what? I will cast and all
peoples on earth will be blessed through
you.
Now Abraham
at that time was called Abraham, Pastor
Simon. I don't know if he he actually
heard what God said. But let me tell you
this, faith does not come when you hear
something once.
Faith comes when you hear it again
and again and again. Faith comes by
hearing, hearing, hearing. That is why
every Sunday you show up,
tell your neighbor, I am a person of
faith.
>> I am a person of faith.
>> That is why I come to church.
>> You see, this word of God never becomes
boring. It never does. Been preaching
this word, Pastor Simon, for all these
years. You too. This word, just one
textbook. We don't have other textbooks.
This one. And it is always alive because
God is alive.
And so sometimes God has to speak and
then speak and then speak because
between this ear and this ear there is a
mass in the middle.
Hello.
That sometimes refuses to open up.
But God is patient. He will speak and
speak.
Now that is chapter 12.
around chapter 15. Now remember when
Abraham was called, how old was he?
How old was he? He was 75.
Now time is going and time is going and
what God said is not happening.
Of course in chapter 13 he gets blessed
with flocks and hearts because he went
to Egypt
and he got it by default.
Hello.
He went to Egypt and lied that Sarah was
his sister. Of course, it is true, but
it was half true because Sarah was
actually the the sister. And so when the
when the AMC or the Pharaoh got got to
know that God was going to kill him
because of this he gave Abraham a lot of
riches
lot of the dowy he would have received
he gave it to who
to Abraham and said I don't want this
cast to land on me that's chapter 13
he's a rich man chapter 14 he has
problems with Lot
same chapter 13 problems with Lot later
chapter 14 dealing with the issues of uh
people raiding his place. Around chapter
15 they are having a conversation verse
one let me read those verses.
After this the word of the Lord came to
Abraham in a vision and God says do not
be afraid Abraham. And then God says
this, I am your shield,
your great, your very great reward. He
was saying, Abraham, I've not forgotten
what I said. I will still reward you. I
will shield you. I will protect you. I
watch over my word to do it.
Now the immediately, Pastor Simon, that
after that statement, the the the
sentence starts with but.
In other words, Abraham is still not
listening. Hello.
But Abraham said, "Soverevereign Lord,
what can you give me since I remain
childless and the one who will inherit
my estate is a leaz of Damascus?" Now,
let me ask you, did God know that
Abraham is childless?
Now ladies and gentlemen, when you're
praying, don't go don't give God
information that he already has.
Oh Jehovah God, you know that I need a
job. H I need a job. God knows you need
a job. What he wants you to cons
concentrate on is that he is your shield
and your great reward. This mountain was
huge for this man and he really
struggled with it. So God begins to
encourage him. Look at the next verse.
Abraham said, "You have given me no
children. So a servant in my household
will be my heir." Then the word of the
Lord came to him, "This man will not be
your heir, but a son who is your own
flesh and blood will be your heir."
Then he took him outside and said, "Look
up at the sky. Count the stars. If
indeed you can count them." Then he said
to him, "So shall your offspring be."
This was a mountain that Abraham dealt
with for a long time.
Now between chapter 15 and chapter 17,
something happened in chapter 16. What
happened?
Okay, let me remind you. So, let me go
to verse chapter 16 verse one. Remember,
God has told him, "I'll bless you." Now,
Sarai, Abraham's wife, had borne him no
children, but she had an Egyptian slave
named Haga.
So she said to Abraham at night,
pillow talk,
the Lord, sweetie,
babe,
the Lord has kept me from having
children. Go sleep with my slave.
Perhaps I can build a family through
her.
Abraham
Maybe he was waiting for that
opportunity.
God had spoken to him. But this guy is
thinking about other things. Abraham
agreed to what Sarai said. So after
Abraham had been living in Canaan 10
years, Sarai his wife took Egyptian
slave Haga and gave her to her husband
to be his wife. That's chapter 16.
In chapter 17,
time has passed. The mountain is still
there. So, let me read chapter 17 verse
one. When Abraham was now what?
>> 99.
From 75 when God said, "I will bless you
and I will make your name great and you
have children and they'll become a
blessing." From 75 to 99, 24 years have
passed and the mountain is still in
front of him and it's not moving
and and and God is wondering when will
this guy get it in his head that he
needs to speak to this mountain.
Hello.
Let me tell you this. God will not speak
to your mountain.
God is waiting for you to speak and he
will move your mountain.
Amen.
>> When Abraham was 99 years old,
the Lord appeared to him and said, "I am
God Almighty.
Walk before me faithfully and blame and
be blameless.
Then I will make my covenant between me
and you and will greatly increase your
numbers." Abraham fell face down and God
said to him, "As for me, this is my
covenant with you. You will be the
father of many nations.
It's not just a son I will give you. I
will make you a father of many nations.
Next verse.
No longer will you be called Abraham.
Now that this is was now this was
important.
No longer will you be called Abraham.
Your name will be Abraham.
For I have made you a father of many
nations.
I will make you very fruitful. I'm
talking for to somebody who has a
business that is not doing very well. I
will make you to be very fruitful. I
will make nations of you and kings will
come from you. I will establish my
covenant as an everlasting covenant
between me and you and your descendants
after you for the generations to come.
Now the name change pastor Simon was
important because he wanted to give
Abraham something to say. Then in verse
15 of that same chapter he says this
chapter 15 God also said to Abraham as
for Sarai your wife you are no longer to
call her Sarai her name will be what?
>> Sarah I will bless her and will surely
give you a son by her. I will bless her
so that she'll be the mother of nations.
Kings of peoples will come from her.
Now let me ask you, when was Isaac born?
How old was Abraham?
How old was Abraham when Isaac was born?
100.
So between 99 and 100,
Abraham and Sarai started to speak to
each other because the mountain was not
out there. The mountain was between
them.
Sarai was barren past menopause. Tell
your neighbor, "Amen."
>> Abraham
could now not make anybody conceive.
He had already made Haga conceive, but
now he could not. In other words, it was
a situation that could not be changed.
It was now a mountain. But God gave them
something to say. So every day Abraham
would wake up and said, "Mother of many
nations, I need tea."
And Sarah would said, "Father of many
nation, come for tea. Come for tea, my
people."
For one year they called each other
those names
until the mountain began to melt.
One year. In one year, things shifted.
24 years the mountain looked at them. In
one year, God shifted that situation
because they changed how they spoke to
the mountain. They spoke to themselves.
Mother of many nations, father of many
nations, kings are going to come out of
you. Nations are going to come out of
you. And they spoke to one another. They
began to change their physiology and
their biolog biological situation and
their chemical environment environments
and something began to shift and to
change. I'm talking to somebody here.
You're facing a mountain. It is
important what you say to that mountain.
Say to that mountain, move from here to
there and it shall be done for you, says
the Lord.
What you say matters. And so they spoke
to each other. Can you imagine the
neighbors?
What the neighbors would say?
They hearing each other. These people
used to call themselves Abraham and
Sarai. Now they are saying Abraham
Sarah, what has happened? And they did
not care. They just kept calling them
that one. They the two of them kept
talking to each other, talking to each
other. And after a while, what they said
mattered a lot.
At the end of the day, they could laugh
because Isaac was born. Hallelujah.
Let me tell you this.
God wants to change your situation.
The Bible says in Job 22:28, "You shall
declare a thing
and it shall be done for you." What is
this mountain?
Speak to it. Tomorrow may look the same.
Tomorrow, speak to it. Next week it
looks the same. Speak to it.
Speak to it because something will begin
to happen.
I'm talking to somebody here who has not
got promotion for a long time. You have
done all you have gone to school. You
have done all the test they need exams.
You you've got the the papers. No
promotion. But today
you're going to enter that office and
say my office is shifting to the
director's office.
Somebody saying where do you think the
director will go?
Uh the director is that God is going to
promote the director to even greater
heights. Let me tell you this. Some
people are waiting to be promoted but
you're not saying say anything about it.
I'm saying begin to speak. begin to
declare it.
But one of the most challenging things
is not what you say outward, is what you
say inward. Because you're talking to
yourself.
What you say must assure you. Listen to
Psalms 103. The psalmist is talking to
himself. Verse 1 to5, the Bible says
this.
Praise the Lord who
my soul
all my inmost being praise his holy
name.
Praise the Lord my soul and forget not
all his benefits.
Who forgives all your sins and heals all
your diseases. Who redeems your life
from the pit and crowns you with love
and compassion. who satisfies your
desires with good things so that your
your youth is renewed like the eagles.
Talk to yourself.
Say these things to yourself. Bless the
Lord, oh my soul. Talk to talk to
yourself. The book of Mark 5:25 has a
woman who spoke to herself. The Bible
says this, "And a woman was there who
had been subject to bleeding for 12
years. And 12 years, Pastor Simon, is a
long time.
She had suffered a great deal under the
care of many doctors and had spent all
she had. Yet, instead of getting better,
she grew worse.
When she heard about Jesus, she came up
behind him in the crowd and touched his
cloak because she thought and she had
been saying to herself,
"If I just
touch his clothes, I will be healed."
Immediately her bleeding stopped and she
felt in her body that she was freed from
her suffering. At once Jesus realized
that power had gone out from him. He
turned around in the crowd and asked,
"Who touched my clothes?
You see the people crowding against you.
His disciples answered and yet you can
ask who touched me. But Jesus kept
looking around to see who had done it.
Let me tell you this. God is depending
on your testimony.
God wants to hear your testimony. Then
the woman knowing what had happened to
her came and fell at his feet and
trembling with fear told him the whole
truth. Something changed.
Pastor Simon, there's a lady who sent a
testimony and it reminded me about this
story of uh Abraham waiting for a long
time. So, let me just read it briefly
and this is what she says.
My name is Jerusha Wera Mugo.
Um,
a cousin to one of our members by the
name of Daniel Moredi. Him and his wife
introduced me to Parkland's Baptist
Church and they have been my mentors. I
used to work in Nairobi and in December
2019 I got another job that forced me
that forced me uh that forced me uh that
forced me to move to Mombasa.
It was difficult for me to accept the
change since I had started loving city
life. May Mombasa become a city.
Right here it says I was 24 years old at
that time. So she had a lot of dreams.
This led me to ask senior pastor Ambrose
to pray for me on a certain Wednesday
service January 2020.
So I moved to Mombasa and assumed an
online church membership. I hardly miss.
Of course, Pastor Ambrose keeps telling
us to get passports. And on the 24th
November 2022, my passport was issued.
During the anointing service, January
2023, I tuned in online with my olive
oil and the prayers and and and after
the prayers, I anointed my passport.
I hope she did not dip her passport in
oil.
I anointed my passport with the
anointing oil amongst the many things I
was trusting God for.
The theme year, the theme for that year
was the year of the Lord's empowered
world changers. So I became a world
changer for real. Number one, in May
2023, I had an opportunity to go for
work training in Milan, Italy.
In May 2023, same month, the same year,
I went to another training in Congo,
Brazville.
Three, in June 2024, I went to another 3
weeks training in South Africa,
Pritoria.
Four, in January 2025, I went for a 3
weeks training in India, New Delhi.
Pastor Ambrose, God bless you so much.
So today, as I write, I'm preparing for
another interview
um with the US Defense Threat Reduction
Agency.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, God is a good God.
>> God.
>> And then she says, I'm honored to share
my testimony. Though a snippet of it,
pastor, you have prophesied over my life
many times and I know. And then he put
this in brackets. Ambassador Jerusha
will one day manifest.
You know there are some people who take
some messages very seriously
and pastor Simon you have heard those
testimonies over and over again because
some people began to talk to themselves
that word ambassador for example in 19 I
got saved in 1974
and around 1976 I I joined Parkland's
Baptist Church and during that time I
gave myself a
I was called Ambrose Alan Nyanga even
though sometimes people call me Nyanga.
This is just to help you.
My name does not have an apostrophe up
and down and it doesn't finish with a U.
So my name is not Ambrose Allan Hyena.
God is good. But at that time in my
young age I called myself Triple Ambrose
Allen Ambassador
and I kept I wrote it in everywhere. I
wrote it on my books and I I read I said
that all the time. I I identified myself
with going places.
And today I walk in that manifestation.
You are what you are today because of
what you said yesterday.
But don't rely on yesterday. Today you
can shift your journey. Today something
can shift because you're going to change
your tomorrow. I'm saying your tomorrow
is going to be amazing in Jesus name.
When I went to the US and I shared this
story in the first service
during summer the international students
don't have anywhere to go
everybody else goes back to their homes
but the international students have to
stay on campus but that particular year
first year I decided I was going to
missions
I was in the state called Ians though
Kenyans say a cancansas
so tell your neighbor it is not a
cancansas
it is a Kansas. Just try and say it.
Arkansas.
I went for missions in the neighboring
state. It is called Louisiana.
Went there with some of our students,
traveled by bus for 10 hours to New
Orleans. And from there, we got the our
our hosts and I went to a place called
Lake Charles
down at the gaff. And there I spent time
with that pastor preaching, doing Sunday
school, visitations and all kinds of
things for 10 weeks.
After 10 weeks, we were to travel back
to New Orleans, gather the rest of the
students and drive back to Arkansas.
When we arrived at New Orleans,
in my shock,
the students we had come with had left
the previous day.
Now it was important at that time what I
say to myself because it is in a crisis
you must measure what will I say to
myself it doesn't matter what will what
will people think now what you say to
yourself is important and I remember I
was the pastor told me why don't I go
back with you to Lake Charles I said no
I'm not going to like Charles I'm going
to I'm going back to Arkansas I've
stayed for 10 weeks here I miss school I
want to go back to school
then I went to a corner and I prayed I
said Lord Lord and you can imagine my
first statement. Lord, how could you do
this
the but then in my next statement I said
Ambrose you're going to college
today today
how you're going you don't know but you
are going and Lord thank you for have
having brought me here for 10 weeks but
today I'm going to Arkansas.
While I was making those statements, the
pastor calls me. He says, "There's a
call for you." So I went picked the call
and it was the one who had organized our
trip and he was calling me saying,
"Ambro, we are very sorry." I was about
to tell him, "Yes, you better be sorry
for keeping here me here for a long
time." He said, "But I'm calling you to
let you know that just stay where you
are because we have already booked a
ticket for you to fly back to Arkansas."
[Applause]
I could imagine my friends yesterday who
went in the bus
for 10 hours.
Ambrose was about to
look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor you're about to get a whi
miracle.
Somebody better give yourself a big
hand.
While I was wondering what to do, God
had already decided
what he was going to do. Right now in
your situation, God has already decided
what he has purposed for you. For I know
the plans I have for you. Plans for
welfare are not for evil to give you a
future and a hope. God has it all
planned. All things work
together for good. So I fly back to
Arkansas. And so I arrive at the airport
and I'm wondering where I am going is
one hour. How am I going to get
transport? While I'm still thinking like
that for some Simon, I hear from the
intercom, I'm Rosyo. I'm Rosyo. Can you
report at the information desk? I looked
around. I said, who knows me?
I thought it was the FBI. I'm just
checking. What have I done?
So I go to the information desk and they
say uh Ambrose um we have a taxi for you
that is taking you to true college
from Louisiana
from the airport where
tell your neighbor that is your portion.
>> Somebody better give God another big
hand.
Hallelujah.
Many of us have missed our miracle
because of what we started telling
ourselves.
The children of Israel 11 days to 11
days from Egypt to Israel. But it took
them 40 years. Another generation had to
be the ones to inherit. Let me tell you
this. You can break the journey of your
past generation and open a new
generation by what you say. What you say
to your children, what you say to your
to your dad, what you say to your
mother, what your mother says to you.
Hallelujah. What you say to yourself,
especially what you say to yourself.
Some of us say things like this, nothing
good ever happens to me. From today,
miracles are happening to you. Jesus
name. Jesus name. Let me tell you this.
You're going to be the first one in your
family to have a university degree
>> in Jesus name. Somebody better receive
that. Ah we are just sending the word.
It's coming your way in Jesus name. Your
children will be mighty in the land. I'm
talking to to a to to a parent. Your
children will be mighty in the land.
>> But that child currently is in custody.
That child is in custody. He's in
prison. Let me tell you this. That child
will not stay in custody because that
child will be mighty in the land and he
will come out and do great and mighty
things. Why? We are speaking to our
mountains.
We are changing atmospheres.
That debt you have will be cancelled
>> in Jesus name.
>> Somebody missed that. I'm saying that
debt you have will be cancelled in Jesus
name. Amen.
>> Something is shifting
what you say to yourself.
Joel 3:10. Just put that and then I will
summarize the rest. Joel 3:10 is an
interesting verse. It says, "Bet your
plowshares into swords and your pruning
hooks into spears.
Let the weakling
say
I'm strong because what you say
matters. Are you weak?
Start saying
>> don't say I'm weak because when you say
I'm weak, you're still establishing your
weakness. Don't say I'm poor.
Let the poor say I'm rich.
Let the down trod them say we are flying
like eagles in Jesus name. What you say
matters. But let me say this. What you
say about God upward also matters. The
Bible says in Matthew 16
verse 13 the disciples were being asked
a question by Jesus. When Jesus came to
the region of Cesaria Philippi, he asked
his disciples, "Who do people say the
son of man is?" They replied, "Some say
John the Baptist, others say Elijah, and
still others
Jeremiah or one of the prophets.
But what about you?" He asked, "Who do
you say I am?"
Simon Peter answered, "You are the
Messiah,
the Son of the living God." Jesus
replied, "Blessed are you, Simon, son of
Jonah, for this was not revealed to you
by flesh and blood, but by my father in
heaven." And then he says this, "And I
tell you that you are Peter, and on this
rock, and I want to say this, uh, Pastor
Simon in parenthesis in brackets, and on
this rock, this confession you have made
about me, I will build my church. this
confession, what you have said about me,
I'll build things on it.
To Abraham, he said, "I am your shield
and your great reward." Abraham needed
to say that revelation. Uh when Moses
said, "God, who will I say you are?" And
God says, "Tell them I am who I am."
God has revealed himself in many ways.
He is your supplier. He's your
resurrection. He's your life. He's
waiting for you to say, "Who do people
say I am?" Don't say things like this.
You know, God has forgotten me.
God is a God who remembers.
May the Lord remember you.
>> May the Lord come through for you when
you need him.
>> And today, I want to tell you this. God
is coming through for you.
>> I'm saying God is coming through for
you.
you. Amen.
>> Let me say this as I close. What you say
will elevate you. I'm blessing you, by
the way.
>> What you say will elevate you. What you
say will promote you. What you say will
heal you. What you say will save you.
What you say will align you. What you
say will identify you.
What you say will deploy you to the next
level
>> because what you say
>> matters.
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor
you're sitting next to a king.
>> Sitting next to a king.
>> Tell your neighbor, I am a king.
>> I am a king.
>> And tell your neighbor if you don't
believe it.
>> I don't care.
>> I'm a king.
>> Hallelujah.
I'm royalty. I belong to the King of
Kings and the Lord of Lords. I may not
look like it, but I am.
>> Tell your neighbor one more time,
especially the one who ignores you.
>> Tell your neighbor, "Watch this space."
>> My real me is about to show up.
>> Amen.
Pastor Simon, who knew you'd be where
you are today,
Dr. Gakunju, who knew when you're in STA
boys,
you'll be where you are? Who knew when I
came to Jamuri High School?
Jamuri High School
in form one that this boy
was going places.
You may not be in any place but starting
today declare it because tomorrow will
manifest it.
>> For Abraham it took one year to speak
differently and things shifted. I want
to say this for many of you this time
next year you'll be in a very different
space.
>> Yes, you better receive it in Jesus
name.
Better receive it in Jesus name.
Some of you have passports and we thank
God for you having passports. But there
are many of you who have passports that
have never been stamped. There's no
stamp inside. It is empty. It only has
your signature.
Hallelujah.
Can I show just show me how many of you
have passports? There are no stamps.
Just be honest because a miracle is
coming your way. You see these passports
were not given to you in vain. They were
given to you to be stamped. Now where
you're sitting,
tell your neighbor where you want that
passport to take you. Tell them which
country.
And we are not talking about Kawangare.
We are talking about
you know you know Dr.
Last year I was in Texas, Dallas, Texas
and we went to a church and in this
church when we went to this church when
we were leaving when we were taking tea
somewhere this couple show uh not the
couple but their son saw me and he told
the dad
there is pastor Ambrose. Now number one
the dad was shocked that Ambrose could
be find himself in that church. We
didn't know anybody. So he comes to me,
he he he um he hugs me, he knows Ma, the
wife knows Ma. And they're just so
excited. Then he said, "Ambro, you know,
every time you stand on the pulpit, you
say those people from Kino."
And he said, "I am from Kino
and currently I am in Dallas, Texas.
Something shifted. Tell your neighbor
something is about to shift.
>> Something is about to shift
>> in Jesus name.
>> So I hope you already told your neighbor
where your passport needs to take you.
>> Once you've done that because I'm about
to pray for you because what you say
matters. I hope you did not say kay.
And from today please go buy these small
bags that you pull around.
Just practice.
And when your son asks you, "Mom, what
are you doing?"
Don't say,
just just continue saying, "I am going
to Dallas, Texas.
I'm on my way to Jamaata International
Airport. I already have a visa and I'm
going places in Jesus name."
Come on, somebody.
H do that. Huh? Do that. Get that
passport stamped.
And while you're waiting for your
passport to be stamped, Namanga is not
far away.
Just go across the border. They will
stamp and come back.
Don't stay with those passports empty.
Bosia is not very far. start make those
movements
because Abraham started calling Sarah
Sarah, mother of many nations. Let me
tell you this, in one year many of you
who have passports that are empty will
have traveled three, four times.
And those who already have passports and
been traveling, your passport is going
to be so full. You're going to have
another new passport so that it can be
stamped.
[Music]
And we want I'm speaking to the
immigration officer, the highest level.
We want to let you know that Parkland's
Baptist Church is amazing at traveling.
So please give freehold, give a free way
for us to go. Give us passports. We are
going places in Jesus name.
Hallelujah. We are speaking to the
American Embassy. Parkland's Baptist
Church has great people, people of
integrity, people who don't sell
tomatoes and onions, people who are
about to do great and mighty things.
United States Embassy Nairobi, we are
saying to you, open that door for us
because we're going to become a blessing
to your country in the name of Jesus
Christ. Hallelujah.
We are saying speaking to the United
Kingdom embassy right here in Westlands
that is people from Parkland's Baptist
come and they have a letter signed and
commended by pastor Ambrose Nyanga
senior pastor of Parkland's Baptist
Church EBS. Please listen to him. Let it
come through in Jesus name.
And when you go there,
hallelujah.
>> Now, stand up on your feet because we
want to give God a big, big hand and
tell him, "Thank you. Thank you, Jesus."
Come on, let's give God a big hand.
So, just just give your neighbor a high
five and tell him, "I'm flying out.
[Applause]
By the way, just be spec be specific.
Don't tell them I'm flying out in number
three.
Uh, by the way, Dr. Gakunu, I'm letting
when when you're flying out, please
choose choose the airlines.
[Music]
Before you go very far, choose KQ.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Start there. Promote us. Then you can go
to Qatar, Emirates, Ethiopia Airlines,
depending on where you're going. Bas
>> and when you go in, start talking to
people who have traveled because when
you travel and enter into a plane and
you start saying things that you should
not be saying and especially if you're
from Parkland's Baptist Church,
Are you whiny free now? Please
what you say.
>> So say the right things. You know why
I'm excited for you to go out? Because
God is going to open doors for you. And
the world is our parish. Amen.
>> And those watching us online, God bless
you so much. Those in the pavilion, God
is taking you far. And I'm telling you
today,
before a word comes out of your mouth,
think about it because whatever you will
say
will matter. Hello.
That song the worship team was singing
about the Lord will bless you. If you
could download the lyrics on your phone
and just read them.
Just read those lyrics,
say them because they are so rich,
so amazing because the Lord wants to
bless you. Amen. Let's pray. Father,
thank you.
Thank you for your goodness. Thank you
for your blessing.
This month we've been talking about
uncommon utterance.
And Lord, we are decreeing and declaring
that we shall be like Abraham. When his
name was changed, he began to speak his
reality.
Even though his current reality was not
equal to what you were saying, but
because you told him to say it,
a new reality entered into his life.
He kept calling Sarai Sarah, mother of
many nations. And Sarai said to Abraham,
Abraham now, father of many nations. And
in 12 months,
something changed. Something shifted. As
I'm praying, Lord, for some people here,
they don't need 12 months. Some of them
need 24 hours for things to shift. And
I'm praying in the name of Jesus that
your situation will shift. For Abraham,
it needed a year because a child is in
the womb for 9 months. But I'm praying
for somebody here that this time
tomorrow, something will have shifted.
This time next Sunday, something will
have changed
because you have changed what you speak
and how you speak it. Because what you
say matters. Father, I pray for those
who have waited for your promise for a
long time and nothing seems to change.
My God, let them start speaking to their
mountains in a different way. May they
not tell God how big their mountain is.
May they tell their mountain how big
their God is. So Lord, this afternoon I
celebrate every member, every worshipper
who has come here today online in the
pavilion and those in person right here.
And I want to simply say to them as a
pastor, may the Lord bless you indeed.
May the Lord enlarge your territory. May
the Lord do you good. May the Lord
surprise you this week. May the Lord
accelerate you
>> and open doors for you that no man can
shut.
Father, thank you for this congregation
and the support they give to us and the
blessings they are to us because every
Sunday they come back again and again to
hear your word and their faith is being
increased on a daily basis. Father, I've
talked about passports and passports
being stamped. Now Lord, cause it in
their spirit realm for these things to
begin to happen. May they get
opportunities to travel whether for
work, whether to visit their loved ones,
whether to just go to another country.
My God, I release that blessing to them.
And they are coming back with a
testimony. Father, we bless you. And if
you believe that, you better say, "I
receive it.
>> I receive it.
>> I take it.
>> It is my portion.
>> And there's nothing the devil can do
about it."
>> Now, give God a big hand and tell him
thank you. Come on. Come on, somebody.
Come on, give God a shout.
Amen.
As Pastor Simon makes his way here, let
me urge you to get a copy of this book
for yourself or for your friend or for
your house group leader or for whoever
that you feel that this book would
become a blessing to them. And God bless
you so much for coming to church today.
You look amazing. I'm saying you look
amazing.
One more time, give your neighbor a high
five and tell them, "I'm flying
on a plane."
Pastor Simon.
>> Hallelujah.
Harus.